I'm a relationship builder.
我是一位关系缔造者。
When you think of a relationship builder,
当你想到这个词，
don't you just automatically think "architect?"
你第一时间会不会想到建筑师？
Probably not.
可能不会吧。
That's because most people think architects design buildings and cities,
因为一般人认为，建筑师只会设计大楼或城市而已。
but what we really design are relationships,
但我们实际上设计的就是关系。
because cities are about people.
因为城市离不开人，
They're places where people come together for all kinds of exchange.
是人们相聚做各种交换的地方。
And besides, skylines are highly specific urban habitats
此外，天际线能反映出城市特有的居住生活型态，
with their own insects, plants and animals,
独特的昆虫、植物和动物，
and even their own weather.
甚至城市本身的气候。
But today, urban habitats are out of balance.
但时至今日，城市的居住环境已失去平衡。
Climate change, together with political and economic troubles, are having an impact;
全球的气候变化，伴随政治和经济问题，正在冲击着我们的城市；
they're adding up and stressing out cities and us,
它们凝聚了庞大的压力堆迭在城市和我们，
the people who live in them.
这些居住在城市里的居民身上。
For me, the field of ecology has provided important insight,
对我而言，生态学正好提供了我一个重要的设计感悟，
because ecologists don't just look at individual species on their own,
因为生态学本身不会只关注单一生物，
they look at the relationships between living things
而是关注生态体系内所有的生物
and their environment.
以及周遭环境彼此间的关系。
They look at how all the diverse parts of the ecosystem are interconnected,
它们会关注生态体系内所有不同物种间的连结关系，
and it's actually this balance, this web of life, that sustains life.
而实际上，均衡的生命网络，才是永续生命的关键。
My team and I have been applying insights from ecology to architecture
我和我的团队已经将生态学的观察应用在建筑上，
to see how physical space can help build stronger relationships.
用它来观察实体空间要如何设计才能协助我们强化关系。
The projects I'm going to show you today
我今天要介绍的项目
use the idea of building relationships as the key driver for design.
都是以强化关系为设计主轴的一些项目。
Here's an example of what I mean.
这个案例可以传达我要表达的概念：
Recently, we were asked to design a center for social justice leadership
最近我们被应邀设计一个社会正义领导中心，
called the Arcus Center.
叫做阿克斯中心（Arcus Center）；
They asked us for a building that could break down traditional barriers between different groups
他们要求我们设计一个能打破不同族群间传统隔阂的建筑物，
and in doing so, create possibilities for meaningful conversations
从而促进各方坦率交流
around social justice.
有关社会正义的话题。
The students wanted a place for cultural exchange.
学生们要求一个有助于文化交流的地方，
They thought a place for preparing food together could do that.
他们认为一个共用厨房能达成这个目的；
And they wanted to be welcoming to the outside community.
他们也希望这栋建筑物也能受到外地居民的欢迎。
They thought a fireplace could draw people in
他们认为壁炉可以吸引他们进来，
and help start conversations.
并成为他们引发谈论的话题之一。
And everybody wanted the work of social justice to be visible to the outside world.
最终所有人都希望世界各地都能看到他们社会正义项目的成果。
There really wasn't a precedent for this kind of space,
这类的建筑没有先例可循，
so we looked around the globe and found examples of community meeting houses.
于是我们到世界各地搜寻社区会议房屋的范例，
Community meeting houses are places
有些社区会议房屋的空间氛围
where there's very specific relationships between people,
在呈现人际关系上有着相当鲜明的特点，
like this one in Mali, where the elders gather.
像在马里的这个地方，这里是长者聚会的地方，
The low roof keeps everybody seated and at equal eye level.
低楼板的设计迫使每个人只能坐着平视彼此。
It's very egalitarian.
它充满了平等主义的色彩。
I mean, you can't stand up and take over the meeting.
我的意思是，你不能站起来主导会议，
You'd actually bump your head.
站起来头就会撞到屋顶了。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
In meeting houses, there's always a central space
在会议房屋中都有一个中央空间，
where you can sit around a circle and see each other.
可以让大家围坐成一圈，互相对望。
So we designed a space just like that right in the middle of the Arcus Center,
所以我们在阿克斯中心的正中央，设计出了同样的空间，
and we anchored it with a fireplace and a kitchen.
并把壁炉和厨房固定在中央空间中。
It's pretty hard to get a kitchen and a fireplace in a building like this with the building codes,
可是依建筑条例，要将壁炉和厨房设计到这栋建筑中是很困难的，
but it was so important to the concept, we got it done.
但它是这栋建筑物的灵魂，我们最后实现了。
And now the central space works for big social gatherings
现在的中央空间提供了大型聚会
and a place to meet one-on-one for the very first time.
以及初次会面时，可单独谈话的地方，
It's almost like this three-way intersection
它像个三叉路口，
that encourages bumping into people and starting a conversation.
鼓励人们不期而遇，进而交谈。
Now you can always pass the kitchen and see something going on.
所以每当你走过厨房时，一定可以看到正在进行的活动，
You can sit by the fireplace and share stories.
你可选择坐在壁炉前分享故事，
You can study together in big groups or in small ones,
或者跟大伙儿或几个人一起研讨，
because the architecture sets up these opportunities.
因为建筑物的布局提供了这样的机会。
Even the construction is about building relationships.
甚至在建造的过程中也隐含着建立关系的意义：
It's made of cordwood masonry,
它是积木式的木块堆叠而成的建筑物，
which is using logs the way you would use bricks.
用一块块木头像砖块般堆叠起来的。
It's super low-tech and easy to do and anyone can do it --
技术水平要求不高，任何人都会做，
and that's the entire point.
这也是设计的原意。
The act of making is a social activity.
建造的过程本身就是一种社会运动。
And it's good for the planet, too:
这样的建筑方式对我们的地球也是友善的：
the trees absorbed carbon when they were growing up,
树木在成长时吸二氧化碳，
and they gave off oxygen,
吐出氧气。
and now that carbon is trapped inside the walls
现在，这些碳留存在墙壁中，
and it's not being released into the atmosphere.
而不是释放到大气层中，
So making the walls is equivalent to taking cars right off the road.
所以选用木头为建材等同于减少汽车污染。
We chose the building method
我们会选用这样的建造方式，
because it connects people to each other and to the environment.
是因为它能联系人与人，和人与大自然。
But is it working?
但这样有效吗？
Is it creating relationships and nurturing them?
它能创造并增进关系吗？
How can we know?
我们如何证实？
Well, more and more people are coming here, for one,
第一，越来越多人来阿克斯中心；
and as a result of the fireside chats
还有，得力于壁炉前交流的魅力，
and a full calendar of programming,
以及全年度丰富的活动安排，
people are applying for the Arcus Fellowships.
吸引了很多人申请成为阿克斯会员。
In fact, applications have increased tenfold for the Arcus Fellowship
事实上，申请书的数量从开放那天到现在
since the building opened.
已增加了十倍。
It's working. It's bringing people together.
它是有效的，也成功拉近了人与人之间的距离。
So I've shown how architecture can connect people
我向各位展示了，建筑设计如何把人与人
on this kind of horizontal campus scale.
在水平维度上连接起来。
But we wondered if social relationships could be scaled up -- or rather, upward -- in tall buildings.
但我们也反问自己，人际关系的孕育是否也能应用于高层建筑物中呢？
Tall buildings don't necessarily lend themselves to being social buildings.
高层大楼本身就不是以交流作为目的。
They can seem isolating and inward.
它们看起来就是孤独和内敛的。
You might only see people in those awkward elevator rides.
你可能会在搭电梯的这种尴尬场合中，才会遇到其他人。
But in several major cities, I've been designing tall buildings
但我已经在几个大都市中，
that are based on creating relationships between people.
设计了以强化关系为目的的高层大厦，
This is Aqua.
像这个大楼叫做水厦。
It's a residential high-rise in Chicago
它是一栋芝加哥的高层住宅，
aimed at young urban professionals and empty nesters,
对象是年轻的都市专业人士和空巢老人，
many of them new to the city.
很多住户还是第一次搬来芝加哥。
With over 700 apartments, we wanted to see if we could use architecture
这栋大厦有超过700个公寓，我们想要知道是否可以透过建筑设计
to help people get to know their neighbors,
帮助居民建立起与邻居间的友谊，
even when their homes are organized in the vertical dimension.
即使他们的家都是纵向排列的。
So we invented a way to use balconies as the new social connectors.
所以我们发明了一种方法，利用阳台做为新的社交连接器。
The shapes of the floor slabs vary slightly and they transition as you go up the tower.
从一楼到顶楼，每层的楼板线条都略有不同。
The result of this is that you can actually see people from your balcony.
这样的设计结果是你可以在阳台上看到其他人。
The balconies are misregistered.
阳台是交错的。
You can lean over your balcony and say, "Hey!"
你大可以在阳台上弯身大喊 “嗨！”
just like you would across the backyard.
就好像你快要爬到对方的后花园一样。
To make the balconies more comfortable
为了让阳台更舒适，
for a longer period of time during the year,
并在全年延长享用阳台的时间，
we studied the wind with digital simulations,
我们用电脑模拟风向，
so the effect of the balcony shapes breaks up the wind
确定阳台的形状可以缓冲风力，
and confuses the wind
让风涡相冲，
and makes the balconies more comfortable and less windy.
使阳台更舒适并能减缓风力。
Now, just by being able to go outside on your balcony
你只要走到外面的阳台，
or on the third floor roof terrace,
或站在第三层的楼顶台阶上，
you can be connected to the outdoors,
你就能置身在户外当中，
even when you're way above the ground plane.
即使你离地面很远。
So the building acts to create community
这样的建筑模式成功地建立起了邻里关系，
within the building and the city at the same time.
不管在大楼内，还是城市内，
It's working.
它都是成功的。
And people are starting to meet each other on the building surface
大楼的住户开始在墙外的阳台相遇，
and we've heard --
我们还听过 ——
(Laughter)
（笑声）
they've even starting getting together as couples.
也有人因此相识而成为伴侣。
But besides romantic relationships,
但是除了情侣关系，
the building has a positive social effect on the community,
这大楼确实可以把正能量带到社区之中。
as evidenced by people starting groups together
这一点可以从住户自发创立团体，
and starting big projects together,
一起做些大项目来证明，
like this organic community garden on the building's roof terrace.
就像这个在大厦顶的有机社区花园。
So I've shown how tall buildings can be social connectors,
我已经示范了高层大楼真的可以成为社交枢纽。
but what about public architecture?
可是公共建筑也可以吗？
How can we create better social cohesion in public buildings and civic spaces,
我们如何在公共建筑与市民空间中创造出更具凝聚力的社交关系呢？
and why is it important?
为什么这点很重要呢？
Public architecture is just not as successful
因为公共建筑如果是由上层所决定的，
if it comes from the top down.
通常都不会成功。
About 15 years ago in Chicago,
大概在十五年前，
they started to replace old police stations,
芝加哥政府开始重建老旧的公安局，
and they built this identical model all over the city.
他们最后在整个城市里建造了很多外形一模一样的公安局。
And even though they had good intentions
虽然政府用意是好的，
of treating all neighborhoods equally,
想平等对待每一个社区；
the communities didn't feel invested in the process
但社区居民都不觉得有参与感，
or feel a sense of ownership of these buildings.
或是对这些建筑物没有归属感。
It was equality in the sense that everybody gets the same police station,
政府公平地给了每一个人同样外貌的公安局，
but it wasn't equity in the sense of responding
但是从各个社区的个别需求回应里，
to each community's individual needs.
呈现出来的却是不平等的。
And equity is the key issue here.
而平等才是关键。
You know, in my field, there's a debate about whether architecture can even do anything to improve social relationships.
在建筑行业中，对于到底建筑设计是否能起到促进社会关系的功能，仍有争议。
But I believe that we need architecture and every tool in our tool kit
但我相信，我们可以利用建筑设计和我们拥有的每一个工具，
to improve these relationships.
来改善这些关系。
In the US, policy reforms have been recommended in order to rebuild trust.
在美国，为了重建社会信任，有些人建议要改革政策。
But my team and I wondered
但是我和我的团队在想
if design and a more inclusive design process could help add something positive to this policy conversation.
是否设计本身和包容性的设计过程可以为政策对话带来实质的帮助。
We asked ourselves simply:
我们问自己：
Can design help rebuild trust?
设计是否能重新修复信任？
So we reached out to community members and police officers in North Lawndale;
我们联络了北隆戴尔区的社区人员和警局官员；
it's a neighborhood in Chicago
该区位于芝加哥，
where the police station is perceived as a scary fortress surrounded by a parking lot.
居民都视公安局为一座被停车场围绕的可怕的堡垒。
In North Lawndale, people are afraid of police
在北隆戴尔，居民都很害怕警察，
and of going anywhere near the police station,
甚至不敢走近警察局，
even to report a crime.
即使是去报案。
So we organized this brainstorming session with both groups participating,
所以我们安排了一场由警察和居民共同参与的头脑风暴会议。
and we came up with this whole new idea for the police station.
最后我们讨论出一个关于警察局的全新概念：
It's called "Polis Station."
我们称之为 “波乐司"（“Polis"） 。
"Polis" is a Greek word that means a place with a sense of community.
波乐司是希腊文：意思是一个有社区意义的地方。
It's based on the idea
这个概念就是：
that if you can increase opportunities for positive social interactions between police and community members,
如果你能够增加警察和区民之间正向的接触机会，
you can rebuild that relationship
就可以重建友善的关系，
and activate the neighborhood at the same time.
并同时让整个社区活跃起来。
Instead of the police station as a scary fortress,
警察局不再是一座 可怕的堡垒，
you get highly active spaces on the public side of the station --
取而代之的是其中生气勃勃的公共空间——
places that spark conversation,
一个能鼓励谈话的空间，
like a barbershop, a coffee shop
比如理发店，咖啡馆，
or sports courts as well.
或者运动场。
Both cops and kids said they love sports.
警察和青年人都一致说他们热爱运动。
These insights came directly from the community members and the police officers themselves,
这个概念是直接由社区居民和警局官员们共同提出来的。
and as designers, our role was just to connect the dots
我们设计师的使命就是把这些概念连贯起来，
and suggest the first step.
协助把这些落实而已。
So with the help of the city and the parks,
我们获得了城市和公园相关部门的帮助，
we were able to raise funds and design and build a half-court,
得以筹款、设计、以及建造一个小型篮球场，
right on the police station parking lot.
就在警察局的停车场中。
It's a start.
这是一个起步。
But is it rebuilding trust?
但这是否真的能重建信任呢？
The people in North Lawndale say the kids are using the courts every day
住在北隆戴尔区的居民说小孩每天都在篮球场玩，
and they even organize tournaments like this one shown here,
甚至还策划比赛——就像视频所展示的那样，
and once in a while an officer joins in.
偶尔会有警官参与。
But now, they even have basketballs inside the station
现在，在警察局内也建了一个篮球场，
that kids can borrow.
孩子们可以借用。
And recently they've asked us to expand the courts
最近，他们请我们扩大这些篮球场，
and build a park on the site.
还打算盖一个公园在旁边。
And parents report something astonishing.
父母亲们反馈了一些让人惊讶的事情：
Before, there was fear of going anywhere the station, and now they say
以往，大家都怕接近警察局，而如今
there's a sense that the court is safer than other courts nearby,
他们觉得这个篮球场比附近的其它篮球场安全多了。
and they prefer their kids to play here.
父母都很愿意让孩子们在这儿玩。
So maybe in the future, on the public side of the station,
所以，或许将来在警察局内的公共区域，
you might be able to drop in for a haircut at the barbershop
你很可能来这儿的理发店剪个头发，
or reserve the community room for a birthday party
或预约公用礼堂来举行生日派对，
or renew your driver's license
或申请延长驾照等，
or get money out of an ATM.
或在自动提款机取钱。
It can be a place for neighbors to meet each other
此处也可以是居民互相见面的地方，
and to get to know the officers, and vice versa.
以及和警官互相认识的地方。
This is not a utopian fantasy.
这绝对不是个乌托邦式的幻想。
It's about how do you design to rebuild trust, trusting relationships?
关键是要懂得如何用设计来重新建立起信任、信任的关系。
You know, every city has parks, libraries, schools
众所周知，每个都市都有公园、图书馆、学校，
and other public buildings
以及 其它公共设施，
that have the potential to be reimagined as social connectors.
这些都有可能成为社交连接器。
But reimagining the buildings for the future is going to require
但要重新想像未来的建筑如何重建，
engaging the people who live there.
首先必定要让当地的民众参与。
Engaging the public can be intimidating, and I've felt that, too.
让民众参与听起来或许有些吓人，我本人也担心过。
But maybe that's because in architecture school,
或许是因为在上建筑学校时，
we don't really learn how to engage the public in the act of design.
我们都没学过如何引导市民参与设计。
We're taught to defend our design against criticism.
我们只学到如何去辩解市民对我们设计的批评。
But I think that can change, too.
但我相信这是可以改变的。
So if we can focus the design mind on creating positive, reinforcing relationships
只要我们一心关注如何利用设计来创造正面、双赢的关系；
in architecture and through architecture,
不管是建筑物本体还是间接从中引发的，
I believe we can do much more than create individual buildings.
我相信，除了外观设计，建筑师是能创造很多利益的。
We can reduce the stress and the polarization in our urban habitats.
我们可以缓和城市居住地的压力和两极分化状况。
We can create relationships.
我们可以建立更加美好的关系。
We can help steady this planet we all share.
我们也可以帮助地球找回平衡。
See?
看到了吗？
Architects really are relationship builders.
建筑师真的是关系的缔造者。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌声）